Jared Coleman

https://www.jaredraycoleman.com

Summary & Skills

I have a broad interest in computer science. My research interests include blockchain, mobile robotics, discrete mathematics, computational geometry, game theory, graph theory, and distributed computing.

Languages: Python, C/C++, Java, JavaScript

Technologies/Frameworks: Docker, Tendermint, Git, React

Graduate Courses: Advanced Algorithm Design, Distributed Systems, Formal Verification, Randomized

Algorithms, Theory of Computation, Programming Languages, Operating Systems

EDUCATION

University of Southern California	Los Angeles, CA
Ph.D. in Computer Science; GPA: 4.0	Aug 2020 – Present
California State University, Long Beach	Long Beach, CA
Master of Science in Computer Science; GPA: 4.0	$Aug \ 2018 - May \ 2020$
Bachelor of Science in Computer Science; GPA: 3.6	$Aug\ 2013-May\ 2018$

EXPERIENCE

The Aerospace Corporation	El Segundo, CA
Casual Member of the Technical Staff	Aug~2020-Present
Member of the Technical Staff	$Mar\ 2020-Aug\ 2020$
Associate Member of the Technical Staff	$Sep \ 2018 - Mar \ 2020$
Intern	$Jan\ 2018-Aug\ 2018$

- Help build simulations for verifying flight software.
- Design software that helps Aerospace rapidly develop scalable, modular, and efficient analyses for launch vehicle verification in simulation, day-of-launch, and post-flight environments.

CSULB Research Foundation

Student Research Assistant

Long Beach, CA Mar 2017 - May 2018

jaredraycoleman@gmail.com

- Developed software and simulations for systems of cooperative robots.

Publications

Robotic Sorting on the Grid

Jared Coleman, Oscar Morales-Ponce

To Appear at ICDCN 2022 - 23rd International Conference on Distributed Computing and Networking

Message Delivery in the Plane by Robots with Different Speeds

Jared Coleman, Evangelos Kranakis, Oscar Morales-Ponce, Danny Krizanc

To Appear at SSS 2021 - 23rd International Symposium on Stabilization, Safety, and Security of Distributed Systems

The Pony Express Communication Problem

Jared Coleman, Evangelos Kranakis, Oscar Morales-Ponce, Danny Krizanc

In Proceedings IWOCA 2021 - 32nd International Workshop on Combinatorial Algorithms

Minimizing The Maximum Distance Traveled To Form Patterns With Systems of Mobile Robots

Jared Coleman, Evangelos Kranakis, Oscar Morales-Ponce, Jorge Urrutia, Birgit Voqtenhuber

In proceedings CCCG 2020, 32nd Canadian Conference on Computational Geometry, August 5-7, 2020

Projects

Secure IIoT

Using blockchain technology to secure industrial IoT systems

Autonomous Networks Research Group & Chevron

2021 - Present

Aerocube @ The Beach

CSULB & The Aerospace Corporation

Distributed robotics systems for space - a proof of concept

2017